Leo Landau

1707 Norkenzie Rd. Eugene, OR 97401 541-513-8720 Leo_Landau@yahoo.com

SUMMARY

Leo Landau has 10 years of experience as a Software Engineer. Initially specializing in creating Android Apps, he now also creates iOS apps, develops web services / web pages, configures cloud services, improves data pipelines and helps to achieve software security goals. Leo Landau creates systems and writes software that works to achieve the goals at hand, collaborating and using data to create and deploy working solutions. Leo Landau earned a Master's degree from the Harvard University Extension School, while working full time. After spending 7 years at Embee Mobile Inc and the company being acquired by SimilarWeb Inc, Leo Landau is ready to start a new chapter in his career.

SKILLS

Products Languages Android Apps Java PHP iOS Apps Webservice API's Python Javascript Web pages Machine Learning Models HTML C++Cloud services Services Attributes **AWS** Hard-working **Databases** Kind **DevOps** Resilient

EMPLOYMENT HIGHLIGHTS

Embee Mobile, Inc.

Mobile / Backend Developer Senior Solutions Engineer Lead Software Architect Software Developer Nov. 2021 – Dec. 2021 Jan. 2020 – Nov. 2021 Jan. 2016 – Jan. 2020 Feb. 2015 – Jan. 2016

San Francisco, CA

- Embee Mobile Inc acquired by SimilarWeb Inc., Nov. 2021
- Over 1M Android App downloads
- Implement new features
- Fix bugs
- Improve product security
- Review team members' code and provide suggestions
- Port Android App to iOS using Swift
- Setup cloud servers in AWS

Leo Landau

1707 Norkenzie Rd. Eugene, OR 97401 541-513-8720 Leo_Landau@yahoo.com

Embee Mobile, Inc. continued

- Create and maintain customer-facing website using React
- Design and create APIs for internal and external use
- Integrate external APIs programmatically
- Migrate server systems to AWS infrastructure
- Implement error tracking and notifications
- Help create and configure build automation and CI systems
- Implement anti-fraud measures
- Improve reliability of report generation processes 10 delays/month down to 1 delay/year
- Improve efficiency of report generation processes reduced daily report processing time from 23 hours to 8 hours while increasing the number of reports generated from 9 to 32

Self-EmployedEugene, ORFreelance Android DeveloperJan. 2012 – Feb. 2015

- Build Android apps
- Create UI's for multiple screens
- Integrate apps with third-party libraries
- Write performant code using concurrency
- Implement communication through web services
- Work to keep on top of the newest versions and features of Android
- 37 projects completed successfully
- Perfect client ratings (5.0) and excellent client reviews on elance.com (bought by upwork.com)

MACS Lab, Inc. 2003 – 2012

Multiple roles at MACS Lab, Inc.

- Project Manager: Supervise and train staff Field Technicians
- Field Technician: Environmental sampling at construction sites and homes
- Laboratory Analyst: Implement scientific testing procedures
- Data Entry: Learned accuracy, precision and attention to detail

Held part-time jobs while achieving a Bachelor's degree	1999 – 2003
EDUCATION	
UC Santa Barbara, Bachelor's degree	2003
Cal Poly, Android App Course	2011
Stanford, Advanced Computer Security Certificate	2016
UC San Diego, Big Data Specialization Certificate	2017

2022

Harvard University, Extension School, Master's degree, Software Engineering

• Harvard GPA: 4.0